Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪I wrote a stroke♪
♪كتبتُ ضربةً♪
♪About you and me♪
♪عنك وعني♪
♪You pass like the wind♪
♪ تمرّين كالريح ♪
♪I follow like a leaf♪
أتبعها كالأوراق المتساقطة
♪But just you and me♪
♪لكن فقط أنت وأنا♪
♪Had no happy ending♪
♪لم تكن لها نهاية سعيدة♪
♪Perhaps it was just a chance encounter♪
♪ربما كان مجرد لقاء عابر♪
♪I turn memories over with great care♪
♪أُقلّب الذكريات بعناية فائقة♪
♪Afraid to lose the past♪
♪خائف من فقدان الماضي♪
♪Tears fall quietly with the plot♪
♪تتساقط الدموع بهدوء مع تطور الأحداث♪
♪Shattered with no response♪
♪محطمة بلا رد♪
♪The wind once♪
♪الريح ذات مرة♪
♪Through layers of mist♪
♪عبر طبقات من الضباب♪
♪And snowy scenes♪
♪ومشاهد ثلجية♪
♪Gently cradled the leaf in my palm♪
♪أمسكتُ بالورقة برفق في راحة يدي♪
♪But♪
♪لكن♪
♪Winds will cease♪
ستتوقف الرياح
♪Leaves will wither♪
♪ستذبل الأوراق♪
♪Our meeting was too fleeting♪
♪كان لقاؤنا خاطفاً جداً♪
♪It's an unavoidable fate♪
♪إنه مصير لا مفر منه♪
♪I too once♪
♪وأنا أيضاً ذات مرة♪
♪Walked through♪
♪مررنا عبر♪
♪A sea of people♪
♪بحر من الناس♪
♪Unafraid of how far it is♪
♪لا أخشى المسافة♪
♪Racing under stars toward you♪
♪أتسابق تحت النجوم نحوك♪
♪But♪
♪لكن♪
♪Time is heartless♪
♪الزمن قاسٍ بلا رحمة♪
♪You never yield♪
♪لن تستسلم أبداً♪
♪Let love remain♪
♪ليدم الحب♪
=Spring Night=
ليلة الربيع
=Episode 9=
=الحلقة 9=
You all right?
هل أنت بخير؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Come, get up.
هيا، انهض.
So it was you
إذن كنت أنت
who insulted my wife?
من الذي أهان زوجتي؟
You lowly commoner.
أيها الوضيع من عامة الشعب.
How dare you talk like this?
كيف تجرؤ على التحدث بهذه الطريقة؟
Your Honor. By the laws,
سيدي القاضي. بموجب القوانين،
any dispute
أي نزاع
must hear both sides.
يجب الاستماع إلى كلا الجانبين.
Why do you take only one side?
لماذا تنحاز إلى جانب واحد فقط؟
I am a juren scholar,
أنا باحث في قانون جورين،
steeped in books and learning.
غارق في الكتب والتعلم.
But you
لكن أنت
are nothing but illiterate peasants.
إنهم ليسوا سوى فلاحين أميين.
Whose words are more credible
من هي صاحبة المصداقية الأكبر؟
is obvious.
هذا واضح.
A so-called scholar
ما يسمى بالباحث
calls people "peasants" at every turn.
يصف الناس بـ"الفلاحين" في كل مناسبة.
Your learning can't be much to speak of.
لا يمكن أن يكون تحصيلك العلمي ذا قيمة تذكر.
I honestly wonder how you placed first.
بصراحة، أتساءل كيف حصلت على المركز الأول.
Are you doubting my talent?
هل تشكك في موهبتي؟
Dare to wager with me?
هل تجرؤ على المراهنة معي؟
How?
كيف؟
Half an incense stick.
نصف عود بخور.
We each write a poem.
كلٌّ منا يكتب قصيدة.
If mine is worse,
إذا كان وضعي أسوأ،
I'll let this matter go
سأترك هذا الأمر جانباً
and give up my juren scholar's title.
وأتخلى عن لقب باحثي الجورين.
But if yours loses,
لكن إذا خسر فريقك،
your punishment will be fifty lashes.
عقوبتك ستكون خمسين جلدة.
No!
لا!
I accept.
أوافق.
Your Honor, please be the judge.
سيدي القاضي، تفضل بالحكم.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Ye Wuming is up against a jieyuan scholar.
يواجه Ye Wuming أحد علماء jieyuan.
Mai Tian's family is in trouble now.
عائلة ماي تيان في ورطة الآن.
You're doomed.
أنت محكوم عليك بالهلاك.
Your Honor, I've finished.
سيدي القاضي، لقد انتهيت.
Good.
جيد.
One by one they come,
يأتون واحداً تلو الآخر،
thin-feathered, sharp-tongued.
ريشه رقيق، ولسانه حاد.
Eager to soar, but never far.
متلهف للتحليق، لكنه لا يبتعد كثيراً.
Pointed beaks, eager to sing, but never true.
مناقير مدببة، تتوق إلى الغناء، لكنها لا تغني أبداً.
Hmph.
همم.
It's sparrows.
إنها عصافير.
(Luckily, few in Penglai Village are literate.)
(لحسن الحظ، قليلون هم من يجيدون القراءة والكتابة في قرية بنغلاي .)
(Just a bunch of uneducated villagers.)
(مجرد مجموعة من القرويين غير المتعلمين.)
(Any scribble will fool them.)
(أي خربشة ستخدعهم.)
What's so funny?
ما المضحك في الأمر؟
Forget
ينسى
the poem itself.
القصيدة نفسها.
Your handwriting
خط يدك
is terrible.
أمر فظيع.
I... I...
أنا... أنا...
Enough with the glib talk!
كفى كلاماً معسولاً!
Where's your poem?
أين قصيدتك؟
At the doors of power, gold runs deep.
عند أبواب السلطة، يمتد الذهب عميقاً.
Hollow titles dress the walls, a lie believed.
عناوين جوفاء تزين الجدران، كذبة تُصدق.
No ink in the heart, a counterfeit top rank,
لا حبر في القلب، رتبة عليا مزيفة،
stinking of money, yet he claims success.
تفوح منه رائحة المال، ومع ذلك يدّعي النجاح.
It's you.
أنت هو.
- Well said! - Great!
- أحسنت! - رائع!
How incisive!
يا له من تحليل دقيق!
Truly well-aimed.
إصابة دقيقة للغاية.
You dare mock me?
أتجرؤ على السخرية مني؟
Poetry is written
الشعر مكتوب
from whatever comes to mind.
من أي شيء يخطر على البال.
You don't even know that?
ألا تعلم ذلك حتى؟
You!
أنت!
(So what?)
(وماذا في ذلك؟)
(In the end,)
(في النهاية،)
(it's still the magistrate who decides.)
(لا يزال القاضي هو من يقرر.)
Your Honor.
شرفك.
Both poems are done.
تم الانتهاء من القصيدتين.
Please give your judgment.
يرجى إبداء رأيك.
There's nothing more to discuss.
لا يوجد ما يستدعي النقاش أكثر من ذلك.
Scholar Liu's poem is refined and brilliant.
قصيدة الباحث ليو راقية ومتألقة.
Ye Wuming's is confused and poorly expressed.
كلام يي وومينغ مشوش وغير واضح.
Naturally, Scholar Liu wins.
وبطبيعة الحال، يفوز الباحث ليو.
This is blatant injustice! What a rotten magistrate!
هذا ظلم سافر! يا له من قاضٍ فاسد!
Silence!
الصمت!
What do you villagers know about poems?
ماذا تعرفون يا أهل القرية عن الشعر؟
Ridiculous! Utterly ridiculous!
سخيف! سخيف للغاية!
A backwater bumpkin
فلاح ناءٍ من منطقة نائية
dreams of playing the hero.
يحلم بلعب دور البطل.
Ridiculous.
سخيف.
Guards! Drag Mai Tian out!
أيها الحراس! أخرجوا ماي تيان!
Fifty lashes!
خمسون جلدة!
You...
أنت...
Wait!
انتظر!
I wrote the poem.
لقد كتبت القصيدة.
If there's punishment, I'll take it.
إذا كان هناك عقاب، فسأتقبله.
You say you'll take it?
هل تقول إنك ستأخذه؟
Who do you think you are?
من تظن نفسك؟
Your Honor.
شرفك.
This man used poetry to ridicule me.
استخدم هذا الرجل الشعر ليسخر مني.
I have a request.
لدي طلب.
Go on.
هيا.
If this wretch
إذا كان هذا الوغد
whips himself
يجلد نفسه
in front of everyone,
أمام الجميع،
I ask that he be allowed
أطلب السماح له
to take the punishment in her place.
أن تتحمل العقاب بدلاً منها.
Guards!
حراس!
It's fine. I can take it.
لا بأس. أستطيع تحمل ذلك.
Hit hard! Make it bleed.
اضرب بقوة! اجعله ينزف.
No blood doesn't count.
لا يُحتسب الدم.
One.
واحد.
Two.
اثنين.
Ye Wuming.
أيها وومينغ.
I've never seen
لم أرَ قط
someone whip himself before.
شخص ما قام بجلد نفسه من قبل.
Interesting.
مثير للاهتمام.
♪Where flowers fall♪
♪حيث تسقط الأزهار♪
♪A familiar fragrance still lingers in the heart♪
♪لا تزال رائحة مألوفة عالقة في القلب♪
♪Youth slips quietly away♪
♪الشباب يتلاشى بهدوء♪
♪Awaiting your glance for a thousand years♪
♪أنتظر نظرتك منذ ألف عام♪
♪Dreaming of the old path where we met♪
♪أحلم بالطريق القديم حيث التقينا♪
♪I watch you gently touch the strings♪
أراقبكِ وأنتِ تلمسين الأوتار برفق.
♪Time lingers on those strings♪
♪يبقى الزمن عالقاً على تلك الأوتار♪
♪For a single pot of tea♪
♪لإبريق شاي واحد♪
Ye Wuming!
أيها وومينغ!
How could you be so foolish?
كيف لك أن تكون بهذا الغباء؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Mai Tian.
ماي تيان.
I can take it.
أستطيع تحمل ذلك.
I'm not done yet.
لم أنتهِ بعد.
Brother, please stop!
يا أخي، أرجوك توقف!
Do you truly
هل أنت حقاً
only see me as your brother?
هل تراني أخاك فقط؟
How dull.
يا له من ملل!
Do the whipping myself may be more interesting.
قد يكون القيام بالجلد بنفسي أكثر إثارة للاهتمام.
Let go!
اتركه!
Whip me!
اجلدني!
Acting out a tragic scene?
تمثيل مشهد مأساوي؟
What a pity.
يا للأسف.
I hate that the most.
أكره ذلك أكثر من أي شيء آخر.
Insolent peasant! Do you know who I am?
أيها الفلاح الوقح! هل تعرف من أنا؟
I'm a disciple of Prime Minister!
أنا من أتباع رئيس الوزراء!
Shut up.
اسكت.
Prime Minister would never associate with someone like you.
لن يرتبط رئيس الوزراء أبداً بشخص مثلك.
I'll report this to the court, strip you of your title
سأبلغ المحكمة بهذا الأمر، وسأجردك من لقبك.
and deal with your crimes.
وتعامل مع جرائمك.
Get out!
اخرج!
Why are you so silly?
لماذا أنت سخيف إلى هذا الحد؟
It's okay. Just surface wounds.
لا بأس. مجرد جروح سطحية.
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
Liu Chen is nothing but a waste.
ليو تشن ليس إلا هدراً للمال.
He couldn't even lay a finger on me.
لم يستطع حتى أن يلمسني.
It doesn't hurt anymore.
لم يعد الأمر مؤلماً.
See? I can still move.
أترى؟ ما زلت أستطيع الحركة.
You...
أنت...
Sister, here's the healing ointment.
يا أختي، إليكِ مرهم الشفاء.
Apply it for Wuming.
طبّقه على مدينة وومينغ.
Hurry!
عجل!
Well, when dad gets back,
حسنًا، عندما يعود أبي،
let him do it.
دعه يفعل ذلك.
Who knows when dad will be back?
من يدري متى سيعود أبي؟
Wuming is badly injured.
وومينغ مصاب بجروح بالغة.
Right?
يمين؟
Right. Exactly.
صحيح. بالضبط.
See?
يرى؟
He's in so much pain.
إنه يتألم بشدة.
Hurry up and do it.
أسرع وافعل ذلك.
I'll step out now.
سأخرج الآن.
Alright, I'll apply it.
حسناً، سأطبقه.
It might hurt.
قد يكون الأمر مؤلماً.
I haven't started.
لم أبدأ بعد.
I...
أنا...
I'm just testing it.
أنا فقط أجربه.
Don't yell. Is it really that painful?
لا تصرخ. هل الأمر مؤلم إلى هذه الدرجة؟
You... You're hurt there too?
أنت... أنت مصاب هناك أيضاً؟
Yes, I guess.
نعم، أعتقد ذلك.
Stop!
قف!
Mai Tian, give me the ointment.
ماي تيان، أعطني المرهم.
I'll apply it for him.
سأقوم بتطبيقه نيابةً عنه.
Okay.
تمام.
Mai Tian.
ماي تيان.
Dad, I'm injured.
أبي، أنا مصاب.
It really hurts.
إنه مؤلم حقاً.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I've been putting medicine on people for years.
لقد كنت أصف الأدوية للناس لسنوات.
It always hurts.
الأمر مؤلم دائماً.
♪The wind drifts alone and free♪
♪الريح تنجرف وحيدة وحرة♪
♪Through seasons, none asks of me♪
♪على مرّ الفصول، لا أحد يطلب مني♪
♪Spring fades, and autumn wails♪
♪يتلاشى الربيع، ويبكي الخريف♪
♪Only the waning moon lights my solitude♪
♪لا ينير عزلتي إلا ضوء القمر المتضائل ♪
♪Love arose with the wind's sigh♪
♪نشأ الحب مع زفرة الريح♪
♪On a cold night, a swan's shadow flashes by♪
♪في ليلة باردة، يمر ظل بجعة سريعًا♪
♪You're deeply devoted♪
♪أنت شديد الإخلاص♪
♪Yet spring wind betrayed your heart♪
♪لكن ريح الربيع خانت قلبك♪
♪I miss you so much♪
♪أفتقدك كثيراً♪
♪I never forget you♪
♪لن أنساك أبداً♪
♪A brief period of love-sickness♪
♪ فترة قصيرة من ألم الحب ♪
♪You won my heart over♪
لقد فزتَ بقلبي!
♪Why did we first meet♪
♪لماذا التقينا لأول مرة؟♪
♪Seeking spring's song and night whispers♪
♪أبحث عن أغنية الربيع وهمسات الليل♪
♪Long autumn comes, and wild geese southward fly♪
♪يأتي الخريف الطويل، وتهاجر الأوز البرية جنوباً♪
♪The azure clouds know my name♪
♪السحب الزرقاء تعرف اسمي♪
♪I remember you, and you understand me♪
أتذكرك، وأنت تفهمني
♪Watching the sun set♪
♪مشاهدة غروب الشمس♪
♪Autumn departs, and beauty fades away♪
يرحل الخريف، ويتلاشى الجمال.
♪To lean on you once more someday♪
♪لأعتمد عليك مرة أخرى يوماً ما♪